# **Emily Traynor**

A professional learner with an eager attitude to develop skills and solve large, complex, problems. Experienced with a wide range of software skills, from full-stack development, to machine learning, to distributed systems, as well as soft skills including leadership, communication, and finance.

EJTraynor2001@Gmail.com Github:

https://github.com/emily0622

#### **EDUCATION**

# University of Toronto, Toronto — Machine Intelligence

Sep 2019 - Apr 2023

Majoring in machine learning within Engineering Science. Engineering Science is an honors engineering program that provides courses in a wide range of fields.

**Coursework includes:** Foundations of Computing, Matrix Algebra & Optimization, Algorithms & Data Structures, Artificial Intelligence, Probabilistic Reasoning, and Databases.

#### **EMPLOYMENT**

# Amazon Software Developer Engineer, Vancouver, British Columbia

May 2022 - July 2022

Redesigned existing S3 Replication feature called Manifest Generator in AWS. Practiced writing high quality code that primarily consisted of Java, Mockito, and Step Function (yml and json).

# Engineering Stores WebMaster, Toronto, Ontario

June 2021 - Jul 2022

Integrated Shopify lite for a popular e-commerce business available <u>here</u>. Used Shopify Admin API, Django, Gunicorn, PostgreSQL, and various libraries. Utilized Python data processing skills to transfer store data to Shopify, and migrated the website from DigitalOcean to Plesk.

# EY Technology Consultant, Toronto, Ontario

May 2021 - Aug 2021

Lead development workshops for clientele and developed on a commercial insurance software called Guidewire to provide customized software features to EY clients. Increased the efficiency of operations through data analysis and programming skills, hosted professional meetings, and gained insurance domain knowledge.

## **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

## EPAI Vice President, Toronto, Ontario

June 2021 - present

Co-Founded EPAI, the University of Toronto Ethical Principle in Artificial Intelligence Club, which organizes workshops and provides opportunities for students to work on technical or research-based projects. Responsibilities include leading internal meetings, overseeing operations, and all administrative tasks.

# Debiasing and Measuring Gender Bias in Word2Vec, Toronto

Jan 2022 - Apr 2022

Recreated gender bias measuring and debiasing natural language processing (NLP) techniques on a custom Word2Vec model, to compare and contrast new techniques and summarize findings in a research paper. Project available <a href="https://example.com/heres/her

# Web Development, Toronto, Ontario

May 2021 - Aug 2021

Developed website from scratch to make statistical plots, share plots with friends, and save data on personal accounts. It uses HTML, CSS, Javascript, and a plotting library called Plotly in the frontend. The backend uses Google OAuth to authenticate users, Node JS, Express, and MongoDB Atlas to allow users to save their plots, edit their plots, and make them public to other users.

#### **SKILLS**

## Programming:

- Python
  - Pandas
    - PyTorch
- Java
  - Mockito
- C
- o MATLAB
- Verilog & ARMv7
- Web Development
  - SQL & NoSQL

### Software/Systems:

- o Microsoft Office
- Git
- Linux
- Jupyter Notebook

**Public Speaking** 

Leadership

#### **AWARDS**

UTEK Senior Engineering Competition (Robotics)— 2021

Daisy Intelligence Hackathon — 2021

Women in Science and Engineering(WISE) Engineering Case Competition — 2020

BMEC (Biomedical Engineering Competition)-2020

BOLT McGill Hackathon — 2020

## **HOBBIES**

Cross Country Running

Kayaking

Guitar